{
    "Maths": [
        {
            "question": "Let the function, f(x)= −3a x²−2, x<1; a²+bx, x≥1 be differentiable for all x ∈ R, where a>1, b ∈ R. If the area of the region enclosed by y=f(x) and the line y=−20 is α+β√3, α, β ∈ Z, then the value of α+β is",
            "answer": "34",
            "question_number": 21
        },
        {
            "question": "If ∑_{r=0}^{5} [11C_{2r+1}/(2r+2)] = m/n, gcd(m,n)=1, then m−n is equal to",
            "answer": "2035",
            "question_number": 22
        },
        {
            "question": "Let A be a square matrix of order 3 such that det(A)=−2 and det(3 adj(−6 adj(3A)))=2^{m+n}·3^{mn}, m>n. Then 4m+2n is equal to",
            "answer": "34",
            "question_number": 23
        },
        {
            "question": "Let L₁: (x−1)/3 = (y−1)/(−1) = (z+1)/0 and L₂: (x−2)/2 = y/0 = (z+4)/α, α ∈ R, be two lines, which intersect at the point B. If P is the foot of perpendicular from the point A(1,1,−1) on L₂, then the value of 26α(PB)² is",
            "answer": "216",
            "question_number": 24
        },
        {
            "question": "Let c be the projection vector of b=λ i+4 k, λ>0, on the vector a=i+2j+2k. If |a+c|=7, then the area of the parallelogram formed by the vectors b and c is",
            "answer": "16",
            "question_number": 25
        }
    ],
    "Physics": [
        {
            "question": "Given below are two statements: In the light of the above statements, choose the correct answer from the options given below. (1) Both Statement I and Statement II are false. (2) Statement I is true but Statement II is false. (3) Both Statement I and Statement II are true.",
            "answer": "1",
            "question_number": 26
        },
        {
            "question": "Sliding contact of a potentiometer is in the middle of the potentiometer wire having resistance Rp=1Ω as shown in the figure. An external resistance of Re=2Ω is connected via the sliding contact. (1) 0.3 A (2) 1.35 A (3) 1.0 A (4) 0.9 A",
            "answer": "3",
            "question_number": 27
        },
        {
            "question": "Two soap bubbles of radius 2 cm and 4 cm, respectively, are in contact with each other. The radius of curvature of the common surface, in cm, is",
            "answer": "4",
            "question_number": 46
        },
        {
            "question": "The driver sitting inside a parked car is watching vehicles approaching from behind with the help of his side view mirror, which is a convex mirror with radius of curvature R=2 m. Another car approaches him from behind with a uniform speed of 90 km/hr. When the car is at a distance of 24 m from him, the magnitude of the acceleration of the image of the side view mirror is 'a'. The value of 100a is",
            "answer": "8",
            "question_number": 47
        },
        {
            "question": "Three conductions of same length having thermal conductivity k₁, k₂ and k₃ are connected as shown in figure. ... The temperatures are given in the figure. In steady state condition, the value of θ is",
            "answer": "40",
            "question_number": 48
        },
        {
            "question": "The position vectors of two 1 kg particles, (A) and (B), are given by r_A=(α₁ t² i + α₂ t j + α₃ t k) m and r_B=(β₁ t i + β₂ t² j + β₃ t k) m, respectively; (α₁=1 m/s², α₂=3n m/s, α₃=2 m/s, β₁=2 m/s, β₂=−1 m/s², β₃=4p m/s), where t is time, n and p are constants, At t=1 s, |V_A|=|V_B| and velocities V_A and V_B of the particles are orthogonal to each other. At t=1 s, the magnitude of angular momentum of particle (A) with respect to the position of particle (B) is √L kgm² s^{-1}. The value of L is",
            "answer": "90",
            "question_number": 49
        },
        {
            "question": "A particle is projected at an angle of 30° from horizontal at a speed of 60 m/s. The height traversed by the particle in the first second is h₀ and height traversed in the last second, before it reaches the maximum height, is h₁. The ratio h₀:h₁ is",
            "answer": "5",
            "question_number": 50
        }
    ],
    "Chemistry": [
        {
            "question": "How many different stereoisomers are possible for the given molecule?",
            "answer": "4",
            "question_number": 53
        },
        {
            "question": "Some CO₂ gas was kept in a sealed container at a pressure of 1 atm and at 273 K. This entire amount of CO₂ gas was later passed through an aqueous solution of Ca(OH)₂. The excess unreacted Ca(OH)₂ was later neutralized with 0.1 M of 40 mL HCl. If the volume of the sealed container of CO₂ was x, then x is ... cm³ (nearest integer).",
            "answer": "45",
            "question_number": 69
        },
        {
            "question": "In Carius method for estimation of halogens, 180 mg of an organic compound produced 143.5 mg of AgCl. The percentage composition of chlorine in the compound is ... %",
            "answer": "20",
            "question_number": 70
        },
        {
            "question": "The number of molecules/ions that show linear geometry among the following is ... SO₂, BeCl₂, CO₂, N₃⁻, NO₂, F₂O, XeF₂, NO₂⁺, I₃⁻, O₃",
            "answer": "6",
            "question_number": 71
        },
        {
            "question": "A → B The molecule A changes into its isomeric form B by following a first order kinetics at a temperature of 1000 K. If the energy barrier with respect to reactant energy for such isomeric transformation is 191.48 kJ mol⁻¹ and the frequency factor is 10²⁰, the time required for 50% molecules of A to become B is ... picoseconds (nearest integer).",
            "answer": "69",
            "question_number": 72
        },
        {
            "question": "Consider the following sequence of reactions: (i) Sn+HCl (ii) NaNO₂, HCl (iii) Cu₂Cl₂ Product (iv) Na , Ether Molar mass of the product formed (A) is ... g mol⁻¹.",
            "answer": "154",
            "question_number": 73
        },
        {
            "question": "A → B The molecule A changes into its isomeric form B by following a first order kinetics at a temperature of 1000 K. If the energy barrier with respect to reactant energy for such isomeric transformation is 191.48 kJ mol⁻¹ and the frequency factor is 10²⁰, the time required for 50% molecules of A to become B is ... picoseconds (nearest integer).",
            "answer": "69",
            "question_number": 74
        },
        {
            "question": "Consider the following sequence of reactions: (i) Sn+HCl (ii) NaNO₂, HCl (iii) Cu₂Cl₂ Product (iv) Na , Ether Molar mass of the product formed (A) is ... g mol⁻¹.",
            "answer": "154",
            "question_number": 75
        }
    ]
}